Did you say the death lament Stratum?
Yep, we're planning on
accepting a request to go there.
You guys feel like tagging along?
Isn't that Stratum filled with creepy
stuff like corpse and skeleton fiends?
You're making it sound like
you're going on vacation.
Are you really going to a place like that?
Yeah, we'll be leaving soon.
Are you busy?
Well, no, that's not the issue.
Now that I think about it, you were
never good with spooky stuff, Lamas.
Is it too scary for you?
What? Obviously not!
Only a child would
still be afraid of that!
Hmm.
Ah, you don't like scary things, huh?
It's just a bunch of moving
skeletons, corpses, and ghosties.
It's not like there's anything really bad.
There's no need to fear.
Captain, it's perfectly normal
to be scared of those things.
You can't seriously expect everybody you
meet to be as stupidly fearless as you are.
Everything I've heard about that place has
been second hand information
could you tell me a
little bit more about
the dead's lament stratum
what do you want to
know the sky overhead is
covered in thick stormy
clouds with constant
flashes of lightning
because of that it always
feels chilly and there
are these crumbling and
decrepit gravestones
scattered all over the place
I didn't know llamas had this much
trouble dealing with scary things
I don't know.
Thank you.
Hey, Lamas, you're not actually
scared of that kind of stuff, right?
Huh?
Well, uh, of course I'm not.
Come on, guys, it's me.
I ain't afraid of no ghosts.
That's news to me.
I remember how you used to be
when you heard a scary story.
You wouldn't even go to
the bathroom by yourself.
You, me?
Ugh, don't bring that up.
It's ancient history. Well,
we're not going to force Lamas to
come with us if she doesn't want to,
so the question is, who's
going to carry Boxo?
Nobody in our group has that kind of
strength. What to do? Let's see here.
We were counting on
being able to bring Boxo.
If he's not accompanying us, a
long-term campaign will be hard.
I doubt the Stratum Lord there is
going to just stay in one place.
The search for it won't
be a simple matter.
Besides...
Hold on! Don't count me out!
I never actually said
I wouldn't go with you.
It'll be fine, I promise.
I can totally handle scary stuff.
How is that so?
You should have no problem going
to the Dead's Lament Stratum then.
Yep, no problem.
Great, I'm happy to hear that.
Okay, we'll head in first.
As soon as we get everything
sorted, we'll be right behind you.
Oh, Phil Mina's not coming?
Oh, she decided to sit this one out.
The vice captain gets
frightened pretty easily.
Yep, yep.
Must be nice for her.
Here we are.
This will be our home base for a while.
You're saying we're going to
make a camp in a place like this?
She's such a chicken.
She's practically clucking.
If you can't handle it
anymore, just say the word.
We'll turn around and go back
to the Clearflow Lake Stratom.
Hope you were d-d-d-diculous, I'm fine!
You don't have to worry one bit!
Alright then, let's check it out!
Ah, there you are. Welcome.
I've been awaiting your arrival.
Who?
I figured she was lying, but this
is even worse than I expected.
Believe it or not, she's handled it well.
Trust me.
Carrying her to her room won't be a
problem, but what do we do about Boxo?
Oh, nice one, Boxo.
Madam, do you mind if we get
Boxo set up in front of the inn?
Not at all.
This must be the magic item with a mind of
its own that I've heard
so much about recently,
right?
How mysterious.
It's funny.
So much has changed, but Lamas
is still the same as ever.
As soon as you began telling
a scary story just like that,
she'd cover her ears and
start screaming bloody murder.
It takes me right back.
Hulemy likes to tease Lamas, but
it's obvious they're very close.
They almost seem more like sisters.
Normally, she would have
run back home by now.
I guess she can't bear to leave this time.
I hope she's not forcing
herself to stay because
she's afraid that there'd
be nobody left to carry me.
By the way,
something tells me you're
misinterpreting the situation,
so I might as well tell you the
truth why Lamas is being so stubborn.
Wait, it might hurt her
feelings if I do. Too bad!
Well, I bet you'll figure
it out if you think it over.
Hmm?
What could it be?
Huh?
Wait a sec.
Those are flame skulls.
But for some reason, they're
just wandering around.
What are they doing?
This is kind of like one
of those haunted houses.
I'll play it safe and put up a barrier.
This might be a good chance to see if
any anti-undead remedies actually work.
Well, salt is the old standard.
Rock salt should do the trick.
Nothing, huh?
You can't trust the old tails, I guess.
Maybe this will work.
This is supposed to be good
for dealing with spirits.
Take that!
Huh?
I really thought that would work.
Could it be I need more of them?
Morning, Boxo.
Did you get any sleep last night?
Where did this come from?
I tried all sorts of things,
but none of them had any effect
on these otherworldly monsters.
As soon as Shui and the others arrived,
Captain Kerioyl immediately sent
them out again to survey the area.
The captain mentioned something about
gathering allies to help tackle the stratum,
and then went off on his own.
Oh, Mr. Boxxo.
I hope you weren't too surprised
by last night's spectacle.
When did she get here?
She came out of nowhere.
In this place, whenever night falls,
monsters tend to gather, even
in the middle of the village.
Only those who are confident venture out
at night, but not all of them make it back.
I kind of wish you had
told me that ahead of time.
You see, the monsters in
this stratum envy the living.
Of course, that means
you're safe from them.
I sincerely doubt they'd attack you.
So that's why they pretty
much left me alone.
They were just trying to
look into the buildings.
You're more akin to them not being alive.
Marvelous.
I didn't mean any offense by that.
Well,
I'm basically a vending machine being
possessed by the soul of a human,
So you're not exactly wrong.
That said, I'm not so sure that I'm
more akin to a ghost than you are.
Sorry about yesterday, Boxo.
It's my fault. Hello there!
I don't know how much longer
I can keep this up. Too bad.
Yeah, you're right.
This is going really bad. Uh-oh.
She's in negative mode.
and taking my canned responses literally.
Whoa!
Come on, this isn't like you, Lamas.
If something's holding you
back, then just overcome it.
It's what you always do.
Why didn't I think of that?
Yeah, all I have to do is
get used to it. Well said.
Now, I'm gonna give you a crash
course in beating your fear.
Huh? Crash course?
Right, I mean, thank you, ma 'am.
For your first lesson, I'd like you to
take a leisurely stroll around the village.
Wait, by myself?
Nope, no way, lady.
You gave in too quickly.
I get that it's a little gloomy over
there, but it's daytime, so you'll be fine.
You say that, but the mood
is different around here.
If the Clear Flow Lake
Stratum is a frog fiend,
this place is like a king frog fiend.
That made no sense, but I kind
of get what she's trying to say.
Since you're giving up,
does that mean you're going back
to the Clear Flow Lake Stratum?
I'm not leaving.
Then all you can do is
tough it out, right?
I guess you have a point there.
Okay, there's a general store
near the village entrance.
I want you to get some
restorative potions.
Yeah, fine, I'll go.
Come on, Voxo.
Let's try to make this quick.
You are going alone. Very funny.
Anyway, I'm serious.
No problem, just you watch me.
I'll show you I'm not a kid anymore.
This will be a piece of cake.
I can do this.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
I won't falter.
This must be how a parent
feels when they watch
their child go out on their
own for the first time.
It's too scary!
Aw, there, there.
That was a good try.
Give me a second and I'll heat
up some corn soup for you.
Or maybe something sweet would be better.
Don't coddle the girl.
Sorry, Lamas.
I wish I could help.
You know, when I think about
it, my job is to carry Boxo,
so this training is useless
if I don't have him with me.
All right, fine.
If it helps, you can bring him along.
Hooray!
As long as Boxo's with
me, I'm good! I get it.
In spooky situations,
it's way easier to handle it when
you've got somebody else by your side.
But I'm a vending machine, so, uh,
I'm not sure if this even counts.
Boxo, are you still there?
Say something! Hello there!
Thank goodness.
Keep talking to me, okay? Hello there!
And you better not fall off.
There's no way I could do
this without you by my side.
It's almost like she's a kid
learning how to ride a bike.
I can't give up.
I swear, I'll do better.
Don't leave me.
I want us to keep on exploring together.
I see.
Lamas is desperately
trying to overcome her
fear so she and I can
stay with each other.
In that case, I'll help her any way I can.
This device disperses
scents around the vending
machine in order to draw a customer's end.
Let's go ahead and try out a coffee aroma.
What's going on?
Something smells good.
Now for step two.
Oh, wow.
This music is making me feel
a whole lot calmer. Great.
It looks like it's working.
I wonder if I'm doing too much.
There you are.
Check it out, everyone.
I've got this down pat now.
I'm not afraid anymore.
Good job. Nice one.
I knew you could do it.
All right.
Now it's time for you
to move on to step two.
No matter what it is, I can handle it.
Look who's a pro now.
So you won't mind setting down
Boxo and going around again.
Oh, thanks.
I'm going to have to decline.
She didn't even think twice about it.
Her resolve is impressive in a way.
Ah, there you are.
I've come back with some hunters
to help with the campaign.
The band of gluttons, huh?
Nice to see you again.
And Mishuel.
It's been a while.
Thanks so much for having us. Wow!
He actually reached out
to the Menagerie of Fools.
It'll be good to have
another strong fighter,
but I wonder if he'll be able to
handle being in a group this big.
Lichuel mentioned that he
went on an adventure with you.
We asked him to join
the Menagerie of Fools,
but he wanted to have
a trial period first.
This campaign will help him decide if
he wants to sign on for real, right?
I'd love to join, but I wanted
to make sure we'd be a good fit.
I'd hate to accept and
become a burden on everyone.
Let's see if I can handle teamwork.
It sounds like he's just
being modest, But knowing him,
that is something to be
legitimately concerned about.
Okay, to summarize,
our primary objective
in coming to the Dead's
Lament Stratum is to
locate the Stratum Lord,
the King of Souls,
and take him out.
This won't be an easy job, but I'm
sure you can handle it no problem.
I don't really get it myself,
but I hear humans have
lots of trouble dealing
with dark places and
stuff like corpse fiends.
They do?
That's interesting.
Well, I don't blame them.
I hate corpse fiends too.
They smell like rotten meat.
Yep, one whiff and say
goodbye to your appetite.
I've never thought about it before,
but humans and beast people
see horror differently.
Make sure you come back to
the inn before nightfall.
Everyone, prepare to move out!
Yes, sir!
Lamas, what was that
crunching sound just now?
I don't get why they put their
graves outside the village.
Who knows why humans do anything?
They're weird.
Mikenne, in short, don't know
what they're talking about.
It's for the heck of it.
I don't know,
but if you left an offering on a
gravestone, monsters would just eat it.
What a waste.
Hang on a sec!
I was afraid this would happen.
They're all around us.
You ready, Shiro?
I was born ready, Akka.
Just give us the word, Captain. Let's go.
Amazing!
Look at them go!
They're destroying them!
Now that I've been here
for a couple of days,
I get the sense that the monsters are looking
into the windows with a sense of envy.
I've heard rumors that,
unlike typical monsters,
the ones in this stratum
are made from dead humans.
Maybe it's really true.
Where did you come from?
Please insert coins.
Oh, come on!
Even in moments like this, I can
still only use my canned phrases?
I don't think he means me any harm.
If I'm being honest, this kid
looks more curious than malicious.
It would feel wrong to be mean to him.
Hello there!
Hmm?
Whoa, uh, hold on.
Hey, cut it out.
Come on, kid, don't grab at me like that.
Listen, if you stop doing that,
I'll give you one of these.
Sound good?
All right, drink up. Go on.
Well, well, looks like it's another
busy night for the loitering monsters.
Is that the same kid?
In that case.
I wonder why he came back to me again.
Does he like me or something?
He's probably just a
kid expecting a treat.
Night after night, he came by.
I never expected to say this,
but I actually started to look forward
to our late-night interactions.
Things have been going well,
so this is the first time we've
decided to camp outside the village.
I guess I can't give that corpse
fiend child any orange juice today.
Well, we're going back tomorrow,
so he's only going to miss a day.
A corpse fiend.
There's just one, but it looks
like it's headed this way.
Aka, what should we do?
If it's alone, we can take it out, Shiro.
Right.
I'll do my part, too.
Is that him? A child, huh?
I feel bad, but...
Rest in peace, kid! You best!
Is something wrong, Boxo?
What's with all the shouting?
That corpse fiend he killed. No way.
Could it be the same one?
Huh? Wait.
Isn't this a label from
one of your drinks?
Why would a monster carry this around?
I know I shouldn't blame
Akka for what he did.
It's not his fault.
But I feel like I'm about to short out.
He dropped a copper coin.
Don't tell me he was
trying to buy something.
There's no way that's possible.
I don't know if it was
the same corpse fiend,
but there was one that was
watching us from a distance.
It didn't try anything,
so I just ignored it.
Ah, I see now.
He was going to try to put that coin in
me because he saw others buying items.
How silly.
Children don't need to
worry about stuff like that.
Besides, all he had was
a single copper coin.
That's not enough to buy anything.
Please insert coins.
You want the usual, huh?
Good job!
You all did well.
We now have an idea of where
the King of Souls is hiding.
So what's our next move?
I'm sure you've thought of
some way to deal with him.
Maybe.
I actually wanted to compare
notes with you first.
Do you know what kind of
monster the King of Souls is?
Not sure, but according to the rumors,
he's some sort of powerful magic user.
Yeah, I've heard that too.
He's got a ton of magic power and uses
lots of different elemental spells.
Not a great combination for us.
Got any thoughts on how
to deal with his magic?
Here's the thing.
Don't we have somebody in our party with
the ability to block any kind of attack?
Wait, you're not talking
about Boxo, are you?
Ding, ding, you got it.
His barrier can block pretty much anything
you throw at it, including magic spells.
If you rush in with Boxo, you
don't even have to take him down.
Just keeping the King of Souls
distracted is good enough.
Ah, so that's how it is.
I'm guessing this is the real reason he
was so insistent on bringing me along.
That's true.
I remember that he was able to block
spells back in the Labyrinth Stratum.
What do you think?
I'll come up with a new plan from
scratch if you're not confident.
Your call. Hello there!
I knew I could count on
you, my Boxxo friend.
You're the man.
As long as he's okay with
it, I'm on board too.
That settles it.
As his name suggests,
the King of Souls has a number of other
monsters serving as his bodyguards.
You can ignore the small fry.
We'll take care of them.
Sure.
Don't get too worked up
now, Lamas. Yeah, I know.
Everyone here has come together
to work towards the same goal.
We've agreed on a plan,
and so the rest depends on what
happens when we face our foe.
For now, let's drink to lift our spirits.
Box up!
Boxo, thank you.
Hello there!
Once we finish up with this quest,
I wouldn't mind having
another toast with everybody!
I hope you can see that the
smile is waiting for me.
It's impossible to see,
but it's a special day!
I would like to be a good day.
I want to make a dream.
I want to see the future.
I don't know who knows,
but it's not the moment.
I'll be happy with this moment.
Today's day is a good day.
Thank
you.